<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the Protector. A proclamation of His Highness (by and with the advice of his council) for putting in execution the laws against transportation of woolls, wool-fels, fullers-earth, and other things</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Lord Protector (1653-1658 : O. Cromwell)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1656</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 11 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B20856</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C7150</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">61885990</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 61885990</idno>
            <idno type="VID">190704</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B20856)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 190704)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C23:2[33])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the Protector. A proclamation of His Highness (by and with the advice of his council) for putting in execution the laws against transportation of woolls, wool-fels, fullers-earth, and other things</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Lord Protector (1653-1658 : O. Cromwell)</author>
                  <author>Cromwell, Oliver, 1599-1658.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Henry Hills and John Field, printers to His Highness,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London, :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1656.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>"Given at VVhitehall the eighteenth day of November, in the year of our Lord, one thousand six hundred fifty six."</note>
                  <note>Item at reel C23:2[33] imperfect: divided for mounting.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Wool industry --  Law and legislation --  Great Britain --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Fuller's earth --  Great Britain --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-09</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:190704:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:190704:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>seal or coat of arms showing the cross of St George on one side and a harp on the other</figDesc>
                  <head>O. P.</head>
               </figure>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> By the Protector. A PROCLAMATION Of His HIGHNESS (by and with the A<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>vice of His Council) for putting in Execution the Laws againſt Tranſportation of Woolls, Wool-fels, Fullers-Earth, and other things.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas ſeveral Complaints have be<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> made unto His Highneſs, That great quantities of Woolls, Wool-fels, and Fullers-Ea<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>h, are daily tranſported out of the Dominions of this Commonwealth into the Parts beyo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> the Seas, notwithſtanding the many good and whole<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſome Laws and Statutes heretofor<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> made and provided (and yet in force) againſt the ſame, to the great inhauncing of the Rates <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd Prices of thoſe Commodities, and the apparent hurt, detriment and prejudice of the State And His Highneſs having taken the ſame into due con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſideration, and (with the advice of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>s Council) weighing the evil conſequences thereof, both to the Manufactures of this Nation And alſo conſidering the prejudice that may happen to the Commonwealth in general, if ſome timely courſe be not t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>en for preventing the ſame: And whereas by ſeveral Acts, Statutes and Ordinances heretofore made, the tranſp<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>ing the ſame is prohibited under ſundry great and ſevere penalties; and to the intent none may pretend ignorance <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the ſame, as alſo to quicken His Highneſs Officers and Miniſters, and others, to whom the execution of thoſe <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>aws, ſo advantagious and neceſſary to the Publique, is intruſted, to do their duties therein, His Highneſs (by <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>d with the advice of His Council) hath thought fit to publiſh this His Proclamation, letting all the People <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> this Commonwealth know, That His Highneſs ſhall expect and require a due and exact obedience to the Law<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>n that behalf made: And His Highneſs likewiſe ſigni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fies His pleaſure, That he intends a full and effectual <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>oſecution againſt all offenders and tranſgreſſors againſt the ſaid Laws, and that the utmoſt rigour and extrem<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> thereof ſhall be required, without any hope of mitiga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion or moderation: And if any extremity ſhall happen to any one therein, his Highneſs ſhall account it Iuſtice,
<pb facs="tcp:190704:2"/>
               <pb facs="tcp:190704:2"/> having diſcharged His duty in giving notice. And yet <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> a further manifeſtation of His care, hath thought fit to publiſh the effect of the laſt Law made for ſuppreſſing t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ame; <hi>(viz.)</hi> That by an Ordinance of the Lords and Commons aſſembled in Parliament, publiſhed the Nine<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>nth day of <hi>January,</hi> in the year our Lord, One thouſand ſix hundred forty ſeven, It is Ordained, That it ſhall n<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>e lawfull for any perſon or perſons, to lade, ſhip, or carry in any Ship, Barge, Boat, or other Veſſel, or otherwiſe <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ny Wooll of the growth of <hi>England</hi> or <hi>Ireland,</hi> or the Do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minion of <hi>Wales,</hi> or any Woollen Yarn, Woollen Flox, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ool-fell, Fullers Earth, Clay, Tobacco-pipe-Clay, or any other Earth or Clay which may be uſed in the Art o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Fulling, of intent to tranſport or carry the ſame into any place or places of the parts beyond the Seas, or into <hi>Sco<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>nd,</hi> by Land or by Sea, or to carry the ſame to any Ship or other Veſſel whatſoever to be tranſported, upon the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>in of the forfeiture of the ſaid Woolls, Woollen-yarn, Woollen Flox, Wool-fell, and Earth or Clay ſo laden, ſh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ed, carried or tranſported, and three ſhillings for every pound of ſuch Wooll, Yarn, Flox, and Earth or Clay; <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>d for every pound weight of the ſaid Earth or Clay three ſhillings, to be forfeited by the owner or owners thereof; <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd alſo the owner of the ſaid ſhips or veſſels, knowing of ſuch offence, to forfeit all their intereſt in the ſaid ſhips or <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>eſſels, with all their apparel and furniture to them and every of them belonging; and the Maſter and Mariner<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> knowing of ſuch offence, to forfeit all their Goods and Chattels, and to have Impriſonment by the ſpace of o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> whole year without Bayl or Mainprize. And it is by the ſaid Ordinance further Ordained, That if any Me<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>hant, or any other perſon or perſons ſhould tranſport, or cauſe to be tranſported any of the ſaid Earth or Clay, Wo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>, Woollen-yarn, or Woollen Flox, or Wool-fells, contrary to the intent of the ſaid Ordinance, That then he ſhould <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>e diſabled for requiring any Debt or Accompt of any Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctor or others, for or concerning any Debt or Eſtate, prop<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>y belonging to ſuch Merchant and Offender, to his own uſe. And that if any owner of the land where ſuch Clay <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Earth ſhould be digged or gotten ſhould be privy unto, or know of ſuch Tranſportation by any perſon or perſons, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd ſhould not diſcover the ſame to ſome Iuſtice or Iuſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces of the Peace, within three moneths of ſuch his kno<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>edge, he ſhould for every ſuch offence forfeit Five hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred pounds of lawful Money of <hi>England:</hi> And that i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>uch Iuſtice of Peace to whom ſuch diſcovery ſhould be made, ſhould not certifie the ſame under his Hand and S<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>l to the Barons of the Exchequer, or one of them, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in three Moneths following, he ſhould for every ſuch o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>nce forfeit One hundred pounds of like lawful Money. Now to the intent tranſgreſſors may not be encouraged <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the negligence of Officers and Courts of Iuſtice, His Highneſs (by and with the advice of his Council) doth <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>point, Authorize and Command, as well the Barons of the Exchequer, as the Attorney and Sollicitor-Genera<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> That they and every of them do ſpeedily and effectually put in execution the aforeſaid Ordinance of Parliament and all and every other the Laws and Statutes made againſt tranſporting Woolls, Wool-fels, and Fullers-E<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>th; and that they and every of them do likewiſe in their ſeveral places effectually proſecute all and every ſuch pe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>on and perſons, whoſe Names have been already brought, or which ſhall hereafter be brought to them, or any of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>em, and who have offended, or that ſhall hereafter offend againſt the Law, in tranſporting Woolls, Wool-fels, a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>d Fullers-Earth (in Our Courts of Iuſtice) and every ſuch perſon and perſons ſo offending, to puniſh accordin<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> to their and every of their demerits, and according to the true intent and meaning of the ſeveral Statutes, Law<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and Ordinances in that caſe made and provided, and of his Highneſs Pleaſure herein declared. And his High<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>eſs doth further (by and with the advice of his Council) Will and Require, and ſtraightly Charge and Comman<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the Commiſſioners, and other Off<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>cers of the Cuſtoms in the ſeveral Ports of <hi>England,</hi> and in the Town and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>rt of <hi>Barwick,</hi> That they and every of them reſpectively in their ſeveral places, do take very good and ſufficient <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ecurity, That all Goods carried into <hi>Scotland,</hi> be accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingly delivered and landed at ſome Port there; and that <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>uthentique Cert ficates be thereof returned to the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners and other Officers of the Cuſtoms, within <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ll and every the Ports in <hi>England,</hi> out of which the ſaid
<pb facs="tcp:190704:3"/>
               <pb facs="tcp:190704:3"/> Goods were exported, before any Bonds be cancelled or delivered up by the Officers of the Cuſtoms within any of the ſaid Ports. And further, His Highneſs (by and with the advice of his Council) doth Will and Declare, That if ſuch Certificate and Certificates ſo to be returned in manner aforeſaid, be not returned within ſix Moneths next enſuing the time to be limited in every ſuch Bond, for the return thereof to the ſaid Commiſſioners and other Officers of the Cuſtoms in the ſeveral Ports in <hi>England,</hi> out of which the ſaid Goods were exported as aforeſaid; That then, and in all ſuch caſes, the ſaid Commiſſioners, and other Officers of the Cuſtoms within the ſeveral Ports of <hi>England,</hi> in whoſe hands and cuſtodies ſuch Bonds ſhall be, at the expiration of the ſaid ſix Moneths, ſhall return, or cauſe to be returned the ſaid Bonds, and every of them, into the Court of Exchequer at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> there to be proceeded upon accordingly. And His Highneſs doth further (by and with the advice of his Council) ſtraightly Charge and Command the ſaid Commiſſioners, and other Officers of the Cuſtoms in the ſeveral Ports of <hi>England,</hi> and in the Town and Port of <hi>Barwick,</hi> That they, and every of them, by themſelves, their Servants, or Agents, do hereafter uſe their utmoſt care and diligence, to hinder and prevent the exportation of Woolls, Wool-fels, and Fullers-Earth, under any colour, pretence or means whatſoever; And that the ſaid Commiſſioners, and other Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers of the Cuſtoms within the ſeveral Ports of <hi>England,</hi> and in the Town and Port of <hi>Barwick,</hi> by themſelves, their Agents or Servants, do enter into all and every Ship, Barque, Hoy, and other Veſſel, wherein ſuſpicion ſhall be of any Wooll, Wool-fels, or Fullers-Earth, and therein to make ſearch for all ſuch Wooll, Wool-fels, or Fullers-Earth there concealed, and the ſame being found, to take and ſeize for his Highneſs uſe, as forfeited, and ſhall return the Names of all and every ſuch perſon and perſons from time to time ſo offending, unto the Barons of the Exchequer, or the Attorney or Sollicitor-General, to the end they may be proceeded againſt, and puniſhed according to their demerits, and the true intent and meaning of the Laws and Statutes in that behalf made, and of his Highneſs Will and Pleaſure herein declared, And his Highneſs doth further ſtraightly Charge and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand all Mayors, Sheriffs, Bayliffs, Conſtables, Headboroughs, and other Officers and Miniſters within the ſeveral Ports, Cities and Towns Corporate, and other places within <hi>England,</hi> and alſo within the Town and Port of <hi>Barwick,</hi> That they and every of them in their reſpective places, be ayding and aſſiſting to the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, and other Officers of the Cuſtoms within the ſeveral Ports of <hi>England,</hi> and in the Town and Port of <hi>Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wick,</hi> in the ſearching out and ſeizing of all ſuch Wooll, Wool-fels, and Fullers-earth ſo concealed as aforeſaid, and in the due execution of all and every the premiſes.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Given at VVhitehall</hi>
                  <date>
                     <hi>the Eighteenth day of November, in the year of our Lord, One thouſand ſix hundred fifty ſix.</hi>
                  </date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed by <hi>Henry Hills</hi> and <hi>John Field,</hi> Printers to His Highneſs, 1656.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
